(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T09:47:26.488751",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
明かりがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on...
天を彩った彗星が綺麗だ
The comet coloring the sky is so beautiful.
僕の吐いた白い息のように、消してしまえたらな
I wish I could make it disappear like my breath in the cold air.
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Suppressing it, I sank deep down.
泣き声さえ、聴こえているから
Even my weeping can be heard.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も、僕の青色で塗り潰して
Paint over your piercing anxiety and pain with my blue.
全部涙になって
Turning entirely into tears,
星の海を流れていった
They flowed away into the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に、そっと青を添えたら、ほら
If I gently add blue to the endless darkness, look—
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew right above my head.
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
It dyed the empty night sky.
深く寝静まった街の中へ降り注ぐのは
Falling down into the deeply sleeping town—
誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness could this be?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars flew again, drawing an arc.
もやのかかった思考を晴らして
Clearing away my hazy thoughts,
「いつかまた会える」なんて言えなかった
I couldn't even say "We'll meet again."
星が降ったあとの街、僕はまだ黒くくすんだ
In the town after the falling stars, I was still...
がらんどうの空を彗星が彩るように
As if a comet adorns the hollow sky,
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
The anxiety and pain that pierced you...
僕の青色で塗り潰して
Paint them over with my blue,
君の涙をそっと星の海に流し込むんだ
And gently let your tears flow into the sea of stars.
浮き出たその光が誰かをまた救うから
Because that emerging light will save someone once again.
彗星がもしも僕らのなら
If the comet belonged to us,
この空を全部君にあげる
I would give you this entire sky.
言えなかった言葉の尾を引いて
Draggin' the tail of unsaid words,
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness is it that rains down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars flew again, drawing an arc.
街の景色を奪い去るように君と会えるなら僕はそうさ
If I could meet you as it steals away the townscape, I'd—
星の名前をひとつつけよう
Give a single star a name.
悲しみが溢れそうになること
When sadness is about to overflow,
天球で離れ離れでも僕らは繋がってるから
Even if we are separated in the celestial sphere, we are still connected.
明かりがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on, flickered on,
天を彩った霓が綺麗だ
the rainbow coloring the heavens is so beautiful.
僕の吐いた白い息のように 消してしまえたらな
If only I could erase it like my white breath,
押し殺して深く沈んだ
swallowing my voice, I sank deep down,
泣き声すら 聴こえているから
because even my crying voice can be heard.
君を突いた不安も苦痛も 僕の青色で塗り潰して
Paint over the anxiety and pain that pierced you with my blue color,
全部涙になって 星の海を流れていったんだ
turning it all into tears, flowing away into the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に そっと青を添えたら ほら
If I gently add blue to the endless darkness, look,
流れ星が僕の頭上を飛んだ 誰もいない夜の空を染めた
a shooting star flew over my head, dyeing the empty night sky.
深く静まり返った街の中へ 降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Pouring down into the deeply silenced town, whose sorrow is this?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ もやのかかった思考を晴らして
The stars flew in an arc once more, clearing away my hazy thoughts.
あ、あ、あー！
Ah, ah, ah!
ああー！
Ahh!
み、みなさん！
E-Everyone!
星街すいせいが、やってまいりました！
Hoshimachi Suisei has arrived!
え、ちょ！ や、や、やばい！
Um, wait! Th-Th-This is bad!
みんな、すいちゃんだよ！
Everyone, it's Suichan!
あ！
Ah!
スパチャたくさんありがとう！
Thank you so much for the Superchats!
え、スパチャありがとう！ありがとう！
Um, thank you for the Superchats! Thank you!
あ、みんな今日は、えっと、あ、
Ah, everyone, today, um, ah,
その前に、あ、そうそう、いつもねちょっと緊張しちゃって。
before that, ah, right, right, I always get a little nervous.
はい、えっと、彗星のごとくあらわれた星の原石、アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
Yes, um, I am Hoshimachi Suisei, the diamond in the rough, VTuber appearing like a comet!
すいちゃん！
Suichan!
うわあ！今日も可愛い！
Wow! You're so cute today!
どうでしょう？
How is it?
あ、この、この、この、いいカメラのこと、え、ちょっと気になりますか？ どう？ど、ど、どうですか？
Ah, are you curious about this, this, this good camera? How is it? Ho-Ho-How is it?
え、ちょ、一回転とかしますか？
Eh, wait, should I do a spin or something?
一回転、
A spin,
行きまーす！ はい、クルリング！
here I go! Yes, twirling!
ちょっと待って、あの、や、本当に、あの、ちょっと超緊張してて、あの、
Wait a minute, um, man, really, um, I'm super nervous, um,
天球どうでしたか皆さん？
how was Tenkyuu, everyone?
あの、私なりに天球ライブをちょっと、あの、
Um, I tried to recreate my Tenkyuu live in my own way,
再現してみたというか、あの、ここから始まる、ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、かっこよかったでしょ？
or rather, recreate it—um, starting from here, hey, hey, hey, wasn't it cool?
後ろにも、あ、後ろにもあるでしょ？
There's one in the back too, oh, there's one in the back too, right?
どうかな？どうかな？
How is it? How is it?
ひらっと回って、あ、クルリン。 どう？どう？どう？アイドルっぽかった今？
Fluttering around, ah, twirling. How? How? How? Did I look like an idol just now?
最高だった！ありがとう！今夜ありがとう！
It was the best! Thank you! Thank you tonight!
あ、なんか動ける、めっちゃ動けるようになったので、なんか、あの、すごく嬉しくて、ついついね、すごい動いてしまい、ます。
Ah, since I can move now, I can move so much, I'm so happy that I end up moving around a lot, yeah.
ということで、ええ、皆さん、ここ、ここに見えるものがあるんですけど、これ何かわかりますか？
So, um, everyone, there is something visible right here, do you know what this is?
これ、これ、ここ、ここ、ここ！シャープ星街すいせい！
This, this, here, here, here! Sharp Hoshimachi Suisei!
スリーディー！これ、あ、こ、これこれこれこれ！
3D! This, ah, th-this, this, this, this!
これをつけてつぶやくと、なんと、すいちゃんの、すいちゃんのこのタグがトレンドに入るかもしれないくて、
If you tweet with this attached, amazingly, Suichan's, Suichan's tag might trend,
トレンドに入ったら嬉しいな、え？トレンドサイン？ あ、ありがとうございます！
and I'd be so happy if it trends, eh? A trend sign? Ah, thank you very much!
え、ありがとうございます！めざせワールド1位！
Eh, thank you very much! Aiming for world #1!
そんな意気込みで頑張っていこうと思いますので、じゃんじゃんじゃんじゃんつぶやいてください。
With that kind of enthusiasm, I'm going to do my best, so please tweet away endlessly.
もう後で、あの、エゴサしまくるので、すいちゃん。
Because Suichan is going to ego-search like crazy afterwards.
マジで、本当に、あの、終わったら超エゴサするので、みんなたくさんつぶやいてください。
Seriously, really, um, when it's over I'm going to ego-search so much, so everyone tweet a lot.
ではね、え、皆さん、あの、昨日セトリ予想とかを色々やってくれたと思うんですけど、まあね、どんな曲が来るのか、じゃんじゃん歌っていって答え合わせをしていってください！
Well then, everyone, um, you all did various setlist predictions yesterday, and well, what kind of songs will come, keep singing along and check your answers!
それでは、次の曲いってみましょう！
Well then, let's go to the next song!
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
Because I am a star, stellar stellar.
きっと君はもう気づいていたよ 僕の心の奥で描いた
I'm sure you already noticed what was drawn deep within my heart—
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
that's the cliché monologue I'm going to tell you from now on.
空っぽの手のひらと無垢なまなざし
With empty hands and an innocent gaze,
ふざけてる空想に身を任せていた
I lost myself in a silly fantasy.
今この宇宙に背を向けて 日が昇るまでの時間で
Turning my back on this universe until the sun rises,
漂うままに踊らせて
let me dance as I drift along.
詰まらないような明日が来ても
Even if a boring tomorrow comes,
笑顔で着飾って過ごせるように魔法をちょだいなんてさ
give me a little magic so I can wear a smile.
埋まらないような心があるの
I have a heart that can never be filled,
Just Be My Love
To look up at the stars,
途絶えたかす といきは
The breath of a midnight drama never starts,
美しき遠ささ
such a beautiful, distant sight.
青い星の永遠あれと願いたい
I wish upon the eternal blue star.
Never be satisfied
Human desire's a limitless
human desires are limitless.
Insaneな朝を ざわめきこんぴりけいな感情
Inside an all-out, though maybe complicated, emotion.
よくぼんを ようしゃなく
Well, I want to be reborn,
おもてへと うんだ ああ 一色触発
with all my heart and soul.
It's so refilling, fine!
It's all you need, fill all your life,
Feel all of it, Bless of hope lens.
feel all your life, endlessly.
Reality and dream, Get into this flashy situation.
時代 因果 狭めき合う
Era, love, and destiny intersect,
うつつと ゆめ ああ 絶対絶命
as my pulsing dreams grow stronger.
You'll never expect that flashes backing the Zabadani fame.
You'll never expect what's pushing behind the stars.
吠える火花 渦巻く炎は
How far will the spiral of flames burn?
Zettai Vitamin, You relax,
Zettai Vitamin, relax,
unity is coming to space,
Hurry up now, watch out for a whole new world.
Hurry up now, watch out for the whole new world.
二つの神秘がめぐり合う
Two separate mysteries intertwine.
You'll never know, it's amazing chemistry.
一つにとけあい 光が空へと
Melting into one, a light shines down,
みちていく あらたな世界
weaving a brand-new world.
Zettai Vitamin, Galaxy,
unity is coming to space,
Hurry up now, watch out for a whole new world.
こぼれる闇の中を また一つ光が集まった
Another light gathered within the crumbling darkness,
長い旅の果てに 疲れ果てた歌声を抱いて
holding out a tired song at the edge of a long journey,
奇跡を起こすたびに
whenever I work miracles.
明かりがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on, flickered on,
天を彩った靇が綺麗だ
coloring the heavens so beautifully.
僕の吐いた白い息のように消してしまえたらな
If only I could erase it like the white breath I exhale,
押し殺して深く沈んだ 泣き声さえ 聞こえているから
suppressing and deeply sinking—even your crying voice, because I can hear it.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も 僕の青色で塗り潰して
I'll paint over the anxiety and pain that pierced you with my blue.
全部涙になって 星の海を流れていった
Everything became tears, flowing into the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に そっと青を添えたら ほら
If I gently add blue into the endless darkness, look—
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ 誰もない夜の空を染めた
A comet flew above my head, dyeing the empty night sky.
深く寝静まった街の中へ 降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Pouring down into the deeply sleeping town, whose sorrow could that be?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ もやのかかった思考を晴らして
The star flew again, drawing an arc, clearing away hazy thoughts.
「いつかまた会える」 なんて言えなかった 星が降ったあとの街、僕はまだ
Saying "We can meet again sometime" was something I couldn't say. In the town after the stars fell, I am still...
黒くくすんだがんだんうの空を 彗星が彩るように
just as a comet colors the darkly tarnished sky,
君を刺した不安も苦痛も 僕の青色で塗り潰して
I'll paint over the anxiety and pain that pierced you with my blue.
君の涙をそっと、星の海に流し込むんだ
I will gently let your tears flow into the sea of stars.
尾を引いたその光が 誰かをまた救うから
Because that trailing light will save someone once again.
あどけない大人たちが うろ覚えの痛みで吐いている
Innocent adults are vomiting in half-remembered pain.
言葉はいらないよ そっと見守るだけでいい
No words are needed, just watching over them gently is fine.
希望が落とす影も 悲しみも流しめて飲んでいく
The shadows cast by hope and sorrow too, swallowing them down as they flow.
わずかなきっかけに 指をかけ弾けばいい
At the slightest trigger, just put your finger on it and flick.
離れてしまえば 輝きは消えてしまう
If you pull away, the radiance will vanish.
記憶が温もり満たすなら 早く
If memories fill you with warmth, hurry—
忘れちゃえ 一つなぎの声は 舞い上がるほど強くなる
forget it all; a connected voice grows stronger the higher it soars.
五次元に咲かせた花火を 明日に投げて
Throw the fireworks bloomed in the fifth dimension into tomorrow,
抜け出せ傷だらけの感情 そのままでいいから
escape your scarred emotions just as they are—that's fine.
見えるくらい太陽を 何度でも響かせよう
Let's make the visible, dark sun resonate over and over.
無残な一人にでもかけたら 意味を失ってしまうから
If you cast it on even a single wretched person, its meaning would be lost,
繋がりを何度も確かめて 信じるだけ
so confirm the connection over and over and just believe.
届け手散るのなら すべてが終わった後にして
If it's going to scatter when delivered, do it after everything has ended,
ごきげんに咲かせた花を 届けくるから
because I will deliver the cheerfully bloomed flower.
踊り始めているよ 微笑みを浮かべて
They are starting to dance, wearing a smile.
消えるほど遠くまで 喜びの歌鳴らそう
Let's sound the song of joy so far that it fades away,
運命が変わるまで
until fate changes.
私の特技がー！
My special skill is—!
本音も建前も 駆け引き上手な大人は駄目だね そんな言葉信用できない
Adults who are good at playing political games with both true feelings and pretenses are no good. I can't trust words like that.
便利で快適で 進化し続けるテクノロジー 伝えて 人肌のぬくもり
Convenient, comfortable, continuously evolving technology—convey the warmth of human skin.
ねえ このまますずっと降りやまない 雨の世界だ もう悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
Hey, it's a world of endless rain that never stops pouring. I'm no longer sad, because humans are creatures who get used to it.
そう 白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だっけ 今、君に会いたいと 涙こみあげる
Yeah, what page of youth had turned into a blank slate? Right now, wanting to see you, tears well up inside.
重力反比例 磁場みたいに軽るい君を知って 私の心は
In inverse proportion to gravity, knowing you who are light as a magnetic field, my heart...
もうそのギャラクシー滑り落ちたら ポイズン 何億光年
...if it slips down that galaxy, poison, hundreds of millions of light-years away.
初めてあなたを見た瞬間
The moment I first saw you,
戻れない恋におちた僕は
I fell into a love from which there's no return.
騙し騙しにキスしてないよ
I'm not kissing you with half-truths.
溢れる気持ち抑えきれなくて
Unable to hold back my overflowing feelings,
我慢なんてしたくない もう
I don't want to hold back anymore.
月より綺麗な あなたよ 駆け寄っておいで Escape in my arms
You, more beautiful than the moon, come running to me, Escape in my arms.
抱きしめたいと ただ闇雲に引き寄せる
I just blindly draw you in, wanting to hold you tight.
そんなんじゃだめなんだね
That's not enough, is it?
抱き合いながら 未来を感じながら
Embracing each other, feeling the future together,
同じ空見上げ 愛をつなごう My U
Looking up at the same sky, let's connect our love, My U.
泣かなくていい 僕がいるよ
You don't have to cry, I'm here.
そのイニシャルを刻み込んでる
Etching your initials into my heart.
僕の胸には あなたが輝く
You shine brightly in my chest.
落ちそうで 落ちない涙とか
Like tears that look like they'll fall but won't,
笑顔で 誤魔化す言い訳とか
or excuses brushed off with a smile—
全部わかっているよ もう
I understand all of it already.
許されないのは 偽りの君の星
What's unforgivable is your false star.
美ボウという名の はかない奇跡
A fleeting miracle called beauty.
一瞬のロマンティックス 溶けたらすぐに
If a moment of romance melts away,
無重力状態 死にやしないさ
In a zero-gravity state, we won't die.
思い出も この空いっぱい
Filling this entire sky with memories.
鼓動を鳴らして 愛を上げたい
Let our heartbeats ring out, I want to give you love.
もってけ もぎたてピーチジャス 胸に飾らないで
Take it, freshly picked peaches, don't just wear them on your chest!
その場にや破ってよ 飛んでけ
Tear right through the spot and fly away!
魅力的でパワー 無限に広がる ハートを揺らして あげる
Shake your heart with attractive power expanding infinitely!
飛んでけ 時を越えてく 深さ自分次第
Fly away, transcending time, depth depends on yourself.
ハートを揺らして あげる あげる
Shaking your heart, giving it to you...
乙女生まれファッショネ―ト
Maiden-born passionate...
お前ら！ まだまだ盛り上がれるれ！
You guys! Can you get even more hyped?!
はい！はい！はい！もっと一緒に飛ぼう！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Let's fly together even more!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
傷ついても
Even if you get hurt,
The future is my life ラストへ流せ goodbye
The future is my life, let it flow and say goodbye.
飛ばせ
Make it fly!
もってけ ニューシティステディデイ
Take it, new city steady day!
時間に急のファイト エクスタシィ
Time's emergency fight, ecstasy!
焦がしてよ 飛んでけ おもひどけぴ
Burn up, fly away...
無限に広がって ハートを揺らして あげる あげる
Expanding infinitely, shaking your heart, giving it to you...
飛んでけ 時を超えてく 深さ自分次第 ハートを揺らして あげる
Fly away, transcending time, depth depends on yourself, shaking your heart!
見てたごごくじとびれい
Watching 9 o'clock jumping away...
あ、こんにちはみなさん。
Ah, hello everyone.
ええと、どう、どうでしょうか？
Um, how, how is it?
どうですか？え、めちゃ緊張したー！
How is it? Man, I was so nervous!
かっこいいし、可愛いバッジ。あ、バッジバッジありがとう！
It's cool, and a cute badge. Ah, badge badge, thank you!
ポルトリありがとう！
Portori, thank you!
あ、スパチャもありがとう！
Ah, superchat too, thank you!
でっかい、あ、そう、でっかいちゃーーん！
Big, ah, yes, big chhh-an!
ええ、2曲目は「Neo Stream」、3曲目は「Absolute 5」、
Um, 2nd song is "Neo Stream", 3rd song is "Absolute 5",
4曲目は「いざ、ごくごくじ、どうびんれいでしター！」
4th song was "Iza, gokugokuji, doobin reidishitaー!"
え、マクロス続きだったんですけど、
Um, it was a Macross medley, but
これね、当ててる人いなかったよ？
nobody guessed this, right?
多分、多分いなかったと。
Probably, probably nobody did.
なんか、あのマクロス続きで、あの、もうぶち上げて飛んでっけーしようと思って、
Like, with the Macross medley, I thought I'd get hyped and fly away,
あの、すごい高い曲ばっかりで、あの、なんでこの選曲にしちゃったんだろって、思ってたぐらいには、もう本当に苦しいぐらいだったんだけど、
um, all really high songs, and I wondered why I chose this setlist, thinking just before singing, it was almost painfully tough, but
でも！盛り上がってね！
but! You got hyped!
どうですか？
How was it?
イエーイ！
Yeah!
ありがとうワン！
Thank you, wan!
あ、じゃあちょっとすいません、あの、り、リンゴジュース飲んでいいですか？リンゴジュース。
Ah, then excuse me, um, c-can I drink apple juice? Apple juice.
これね、エアリンゴジュースです。エアリンゴジュース。
This is, air apple juice. Air apple juice.
見えないと思うんですけど、
You probably can't see it,
私にだけはかろうじて見えないリンゴジュースです。
it's apple juice that barely only I can see.
あ、み、みんなリンゴジュースありがとう！リンゴジュースありがとう！
Ah, e-everyone, thanks for the apple juice! Thanks for the apple juice!
そう、今日もね、あの、もうマジで、マジで喉、ちょっともう本当完璧にしとかなきゃと思って、喉飴舐めて、
Yeah, today too, um, like seriously, seriously, I gotta make my throat absolutely perfect, I thought, so I sucked on throat lozenges,
あの、あのリンゴジュース飲んで、もうたくさんやった
um, drank apple juice, and did a lot,
けど、まあやっぱちょっと緊張して、た、緊張してさ、
though, well, I was a little nervous, n-nervous, y'know,
でもいいパフォーマンスができたと思います。
but I think I gave a good performance.
あ、あとね、えっと、もう一個ちょっと言いたいことがあって、
Ah, also, um, there's one more thing I want to say,
マイク、マイクちょっとください、マイク、マイク、あ、マイク、あ、マイク！あ、頂戴しました！はい、はい。
mic, please give me the mic, mic, mic, ah, mic, ah, mic! Ah, I got it! Yes, yes.
あ、出ました！
Ah, it came out!
これ、ちょっと見てくださいよ、マイク！
Please look at this, the mic!
どうですか？
How is it?
隙間なく360度から見てください！
Look at it from 360 degrees without any gaps!
隙間なく見てください！どうですか？
Look at without any gaps! How is it?
可愛いでしょう？ここに、ここに、あのコンペイトウがついてたりなんだりして。
Isn't it cute? Here, here, it has star candies attached and stuff.
で、ほら、ここに、あの、このマイクの部分が、ほら、プラネットみたいな、惑星みたいな。
And see, here, um, this mic part is, see, like a planet, like a celestial body.
私、1周年告知した時に、あの、お友達のね、あの、おもかげがあると思うって言ったと思うんですけど、
When I announced my 1st anniversary, I said there was probably a trace of my friend, right?
これです！これは、えっと、私が、えっと、個人勢時代から仲良くしてくれてた、え、ルピナスナイトリーちゃんがマイクのデザインをしてくれて、えっと、形にしてくれたのは、クーンランちゃんです！
This is it! This is, um, Lupinus Nightly-chan, who was close friends with me since my indie days, designed the mic, and Kuunran-chan is the one who shaped it!
どうでしょうか？
How is it?
あのね、すいちゃんが、あの、少女向けアニメっぽいマイクが欲しいって言ったら、こんな可愛いやつを用意してくれました。
Y'know, when Suisan said she wanted a mic like a shoujo anime, she prepared such a cute one.
本当にありがとう！ルピナスナイトリーちゃんありがとう！
Thank you so much! Thank you, Lupinus Nightly-chan!
ということで、ええ、えっと、もう時間もね、あの、まだありますんで、あの、曲がまだまだありますんで、次の曲に行きたいなと思いますよ。
So, um, um, we still have plenty of time, um, we still have more songs, so I'd like to move on to the next song.
じゃあね、次は、ちょっと結構、あの、ダンスも取り入れて、はげしめにやっていこうと思いますので、まだまだぶち上がっていきましょう！
So next, um, quite a bit, um, incorporating dancing too, we'll do it more intensely, so let's get even more hyped!
それでは、次の曲いってみよう！
Now then, let's go to the next song!
何も聞こえない 何も聞かせてくれない
I don't hear a thing. You won't let me hear a thing.
僕の身体が昔より大人になったからなのかな
Is it because my body's more grown up now than it was way back then?
ベッドに置いてあった初めて買った黒いラジオ
A black radio — the first one I ever bought — sat on my bed
いくつかのメロディがいくつもの時代を作った
All the melodies from it created so many eras
思春期に少年から大人に変わる
In adolescence you change from being a boy to a man
道を探していた 汚れもないままに
I searched for roads to take, still yet to be sullied
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
Just like the shooting star I have become, stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気付いていた
I'm sure that you've already seen through it all
僕の心の奥で描いた
This script hidden deep down in my heart
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
That I will now read out, acting the part
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There are so many things I could not say out loud
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
So many walls I could never climb beyond
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
Sensing the scent of morning wafting in the air
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
I tried to fight it filling me with hate
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて 震えていた
I sat in a corner and cried into my knees, trembling
太陽なんかいらないから 明けないでいて
I don't need the sunshine, don't want it in my life
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Hold your hand out all the way, reach out and make someone feel
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかじゃないから
We're very alike, indeed, both you and me
そうさ 僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night so stellar stellar
ありったけの輝きで 今宵音楽はずーっとずーっと止まらない
Shining as bright as any eye can take, the music will never stop
そうだ 僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ 迎えに行く王子様だ
Was never a Cinderella who waits forever, but the prince
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become
なんて、ありふれた話なんだ
Such a common story
理想だけ書き連ねていた
Just a scene lying dormant in a notebook
ノートの隅に眠るほんのワンシーンだ
I've been scribbling my ideals in
きっとあの星も泣いてるんだ
That star must be crying too
明日なんて来ないままでいて
I pray that tomorrow won't come
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Hold your hand out all the way, reach out to someone
本当に大切なものは目に見えないみたいなのさ
The truly important things in life seem invisible
そうさ 僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night so stellar stellar
ありのまま考えないで 今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
Don't think of things as they are, the music won't stop tonight
そうだ 僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be
儚いヒロインじゃないさ 救いに行くヒーローだ
Was not a delicate heroine, but a hero on his way
夢見がちな童話めいた話
A dreamy fairytale
そうさ 僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night so stellar stellar
ありったけの輝きで 今宵音楽はずーっとずーっと止まらない
Shining as bright as any eye can take, the music will never stop
そうだ 僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be
そうさ 僕は愛を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through my love so stellar stellar
世界、宇宙の真ん中で
In the midst of this world, the universe
今宵音楽はきっときっと止まらない
The music won't stop tonight
そうだ 僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ 迎えに行く王子様だ
Was never a Cinderella, but the prince who goes
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become
そうだ 僕は星だった
That's right, I'm a star
stellar stellar
さあ、行こうか
Now then, shall we go?
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
Just like the shooting star I have become, stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気付いていた
I'm sure that you've already seen through it all
僕の心の奥で描いた
This script hidden deep down in my heart
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
That I will now read out, acting the part
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There are so many things I could not say out loud
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
So many walls I could never climb beyond
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
Sensing the scent of morning wafting in the air
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
I tried to fight it filling me with hate
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて 震えていた
I sat in a corner and cried into my knees, trembling
太陽なんかいらないから 明けないでいて
I don't need the sunshine, don't want it in my life
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Hold your hand out all the way, reach out and make someone feel
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかじゃないから
We're very alike, indeed, both you and me
そうさ 僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
So I sing now through this night so stellar stellar
ありったけの輝きで 今宵音楽はずーっとずーっと止まらない
Shining as bright as any eye can take, the music will never stop
そうだ 僕がずっとなりたかったのは
So I say, what I wanted to be
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ 迎えに行く王子様だ
Was never a Cinderella who waits forever, but the prince
だって僕は星だから
Just like the shooting star I have become
Yaa-Yaa!! 準備はできたよ
Yaa-Yaa!! We're ready now!
忘れたふりはやだ (Yaa!) やだ (Yaa!)
Don't pretend you forgot! (Yaa!) You forgot! (Yaa!)
Aqours☆PUNCH!!
やあやあやあ 相談があるなら (あるなら)
Yah yah yah, if you need some advice (If you do)
すぐに...すぐに呼びなさい! (呼んでよ!)
Then... just shout it out right now! (Shout it!)
ジェットでマッハでそっちに行くから もー (Yaa!) ちょっと (Yaa!) 待ってて
We're going over there on a jet at mach speed, so just hang on (Yaa!) just hang on (Yaa!)
無敵だって信じたくて
We wanna believe we're invincible
いこうけいで We are HEROES
Say it with oomph: We are HEROES
つっついて つっついて つっついてね (Wao!)
Really stick it to us, yeah, stick it to us, yeah, stick it to us, yeah (Wao!)
悩みをぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your worries flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなるって気がしてるの
I've got this feeling that we're gonna get stronger someway, somehow
そんな私たち、だよだよ!
That's just how we are!
さあさあさあ 元気をだしてよ
C'mon c'mon c'mon, cheer up
本当は知ってるででも (Yaa!) でも (Yaa!)
Who, uh... who are you again? (Yaa!) But (Yaa!)
Aqours☆FLASH!!
ひみつなんだっ
It's a secret
さあさあさあ 問題なんだろ (なんだろ) すぐに...すぐに呼びなさい! (呼んでよ!)
C'mon c'mon c'mon, what's the problem? (What is it?) Just... just shout it out right now! (Shout it!)
ショックでダウンで泣きそうなときは もー (Yaa!) ちょっと (Yaa!) 踏んづけてね
When you're shocked or down or just feel like crying, stand (Yaa!) your (Yaa!) ground
ためいきに流されないで (つかまえてよ私の手に)
Don't get swept up in your sighs (I'll catch them in my hand)
もっと前に (So!) ぐっと前に (So!) おいで おいでよ
It's not over yet! Follow me, it's up ahead (So!) right in front of us (So!)
願いは言ってみたくなる ステージ乗って戦いましょう
Let's fight on a stage that'll make us wanna say what our wishes are
かなえたい かなえたい夢になるって気がしてさ
I've got a feeling they'll be dreams we'll want to have come true, come true
だからおいでよ (Wao!)
So c'mere (Wao!)
悩みをぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your worries flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなるって気がしてるの
I've got this feeling that we're gonna get stronger someway, somehow
迷いもぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your doubts flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなる なりそうな Aqours☆HEROES
We're Aqours☆HEROES, and we're about to get stronger someway, somehow
そんな私たち、だよだよ! Yaa-Yaa!!
That's just how we are! Yaa-Yaa!!
Yaa-Yaa!! 準備はできたよ
Yaa-Yaa!! We're ready now!
忘れたふりはやだ (Yaa!) やだ (Yaa!)
Don't pretend you forgot! (Yaa!) You forgot! (Yaa!)
Aqours☆PUNCH!!
やあやあやあ 相談があるなら (あるなら)
Yah yah yah, if you need some advice (If you do)
すぐに...すぐに呼びなさい! (呼んでよ!)
Then... just shout it out right now! (Shout it!)
ジェットでマッハでそっちに行くから もー (Yaa!) ちょっと (Yaa!) 待ってて
We're going over there on a jet at mach speed, so just hang on (Yaa!) just hang on (Yaa!)
無敵だって信じたくて
We wanna believe we're invincible
いこうけいで We are HEROES
Say it with oomph: We are HEROES
つっついて つっついて つっついてね (Wao!)
Really stick it to us, yeah, stick it to us, yeah, stick it to us, yeah (Wao!)
悩みをぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your worries flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなるって気がしてるの
I've got this feeling that we're gonna get stronger someway, somehow
迷いもぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your doubts flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなる なりそうな Aqours☆HEROES
We're Aqours☆HEROES, and we're about to get stronger someway, somehow
そんな私たち、だよだよ!
That's just how we are!
さあさあさあ 元気をだしてよ
C'mon c'mon c'mon, cheer up
本当は知ってるででも (Yaa!) でも (Yaa!)
Who, uh... who are you again? (Yaa!) But (Yaa!)
Aqours☆FLASH!!
ひみつなんだっ
It's a secret
さあさあさあ 問題なんだろ (なんだろ) すぐに...すぐに呼びなさい! (呼んでよ!)
C'mon c'mon c'mon, what's the problem? (What is it?) Just... just shout it out right now! (Shout it!)
ショックでダウンで泣きそうなときは もー (Yaa!) ちょっと (Yaa!) 踏んづけてね
When you're shocked or down or just feel like crying, stand (Yaa!) your (Yaa!) ground
ためいきに流されないで (つかまえてよ私の手に)
Don't get swept up in your sighs (I'll catch them in my hand)
もっと前に (So!) ぐっと前に (So!) おいで おいでよ
It's not over yet! Follow me, it's up ahead (So!) right in front of us (So!)
願いは言ってみたくなる ステージ乗って戦いましょう
Let's fight on a stage that'll make us wanna say what our wishes are
かなえたい かなえたい夢になるって気がしてさ
I've got a feeling they'll be dreams we'll want to have come true, come true
だからおいでよ (Wao!)
So c'mere (Wao!)
悩みをぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your worries flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなるって気がしてるの
I've got this feeling that we're gonna get stronger someway, somehow
迷いもぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your doubts flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなる なりそうな Aqours☆HEROES
We're Aqours☆HEROES, and we're about to get stronger someway, somehow
そんな私たち、だよだよ! Yaa-Yaa!!
That's just how we are! Yaa-Yaa!!
Yaa-Yaa!! 準備はできたよ
Yaa-Yaa!! We're ready now!
忘れたふりはやだ (Yaa!) やだ (Yaa!)
Don't pretend you forgot! (Yaa!) You forgot! (Yaa!)
Aqours☆PUNCH!!
やあやあやあ 相談があるなら (あるなら)
Yah yah yah, if you need some advice (If you do)
すぐに...すぐに呼びなさい! (呼んでよ!)
Then... just shout it out right now! (Shout it!)
ジェットでマッハでそっちに行くから もー (Yaa!) ちょっと (Yaa!) 待ってて
We're going over there on a jet at mach speed, so just hang on (Yaa!) just hang on (Yaa!)
無敵だって信じたくて
We wanna believe we're invincible
いこうけいで We are HEROES
Say it with oomph: We are HEROES
つっついて つっついて つっついてね (Wao!)
Really stick it to us, yeah, stick it to us, yeah, stick it to us, yeah (Wao!)
悩みをぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your worries flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなるって気がしてるの
I've got this feeling that we're gonna get stronger someway, somehow
迷いもぶっ飛ばすような イメージ持って戦いましょう
Let's fight, giving off the image that we'll send your doubts flying
なんとなく なんとなく強くなる なりそうな Aqours☆HEROES
We're Aqours☆HEROES, and we're about to get stronger someway, somehow
そんな私たち、だよだよ!
That's just how we are!
Yaa-Yaa!!
気配が消えた…？
Your presence disappeared...?
私の呼吸が 荒く 激しく 辿る 手がかり
My breath becomes rough as I aggressively follow the clues
探し ながら も 見つけたくない
Even as I searched, I didn't want to find it
見つけたら すぐ 攻撃しないと
Once I found you, I'd have to attack
どうして あなたが 敵なのか (きっと 誰にもわからない)
Why are you my enemy? (I'm sure no one knows)
気配が消えた…？ 私の呼吸が荒く
Have the signs disappeared...? My breathing is rough
激しく辿る手掛かり
and violent as I trace the clues.
探しがならも見つけたくない
Searching, yet hoping not to find it,
見つけたらすぐ攻撃しなきゃ
but finding it means I must attack right away.
どうしてあなたが敵なのか
Why must you be my enemy?
こんなに惹かれたわけさえも
Even the reason I was so drawn to you—
悪い夢なんだ
It must be a bad dream.
光と闇のデイジーン
A daydream of light and darkness,
黒い扉の向こう
beyond the black door.
待ち受けるのは 抱かれた私のロスト
What awaits me is the embrace of my lost love.
あの日知った優しさだけ忘れないと
"I will never forget the kindness I knew that day."
額伝う汗をぬぐい自らの手で終わりにしよう
Wiping the sweat from my brow, I'll end it with my own hands.
心の声を聞かないふりで
Feigning ignorance of my heart's voice,
走る私の矛盾が揺れる
my running contradictions waver.
愛しい気持ち 許せない気持ち
These beloved feelings, these unforgivable feelings—
問い正したい 弱さが辛い
wanting to question them, but the weakness is painful.
どうしてあなたに出会ったのか
Why did I ever cross paths with you?
確かな繋がり感じてたよ
I felt a certain connection between us,
だけど幻は打ち砕かれたね
but the illusion was shattered to pieces, wasn't it?
祈りも恋もデイジーン
Prayers and love are a daydream,
夢は夢でしかないと
knowing that dreams are only dreams.
嘆きの果ての 変わらずにいまロスター
At the end of grief, an unchanging lost star...
乗り越えるまで この涙を飲み込んだら
Until I overcome this, swallowing these tears,
暗い壁に背中よせて 戦いの身支度してる
with my back against the dark wall, I prepare for battle.
でも 帰りたい あの日 出会いの日の
But I want to return to that day, the day we met...
たった一つの願い 叶わない
to my one and only wish that won't come true.
悪い夢なんだ
It must be a bad dream.
光と闇のデイジーン
A daydream of light and darkness,
黒い扉の向こう
beyond the black door.
待ち受けるのは 抱かれた私のロスト
What awaits me is the embrace of my lost love.
あの日知った優しさだけ忘れないと
"I will never forget the kindness I knew that day."
額伝う汗をぬぐい自らの手で終わりにしよう
Wiping the sweat from my brow, I'll end it with my own hands.
ああ！
Ah!
やべえ 汗がちょっと だくだく
Oh man, I'm sweating so much, it's pouring out!
ちょっと あの私にしか飲めないリンゴジュース行きます
Hold on, I'm gonna drink some special apple juice only I can have.
どうですか？ ちょっとみなさん すいちゃんの
How is it? Everyone, Suisei's—
っ、これ昨日の1時で終わったんですよ。
This ended at 1 AM yesterday.
昨日の1時で終わったんですよ。ちょっと頑張った今日のため、今日のために頑張って思えた飲んだありがとー！
It ended at 1 AM yesterday. I worked hard for today... for today, I pushed myself and thought... I drank, thank you so much!
パチパチありがとう！
Clap clap, thank you!
あー疲れた。
Ah, I'm tired.
44分経ってってさ、私まだ10分しか経ってない気持ちなんだよ。44分経ってんだって。
It's been 44 minutes? I feel like only 10 minutes have passed! It's already been 44 minutes?
え、てかさ、今トレンド何位なんだろう？
Wait, what rank are we in trends right now?
え！？日本1位！？
What?! Number 1 in Japan?!
あ、世界2位！？
Ah, number 2 in the world?!
え、嬉しっ。
Eh, I'm so happy.
え、嬉し！ありがとう！
Ah, I'm so happy! Thank you!
超、え、超なんか、え、アイドルじゃね？
Super, like, aren't I an idol?
ちょ、ちょ、な、え、超有名人じゃね？
Wait, aren't I a super celebrity?
あれ？え、超嬉しいんだけどー！
Huh? I'm so happy!
えー！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
え、皆さんあの、
Um, everyone, uh,
えっと、5曲目、5曲目が、何だったっけ？えっと、表面世界の存在論で、6曲目がホテルムーンサイド、7曲目がデッドレーム・モリアでしょ？
Um, the 5th song, what was it? Ontology of Surface World, 6th was Hotel Moonside, 7th was Deadream Moria right?
ええと、デレマス、デレマス、ラブライブサンシャインっていうね、感じだったんですけど。
Um, Deremas, Deremas, Love Live Sunshine, that kind of feel it was.
デッドレーム・モリアを予想してる人いなかったね、さすがに！
Nobody expected Deadream Moria, as expected!
いや、この曲すっごい大好きで、踊りもかっこいいじゃないですか。チェンチェンテンテンテンテンテンテンみたいな。
Man, I love this song so much, and the dance is cool, right? Like *chen chen ten ten...*
もう、それがね、あの、すごい大変だったんだけど、でも踊るのすごい楽しかった。
That was super tough, but dancing it was super fun.
皆さんありがとう！メンバーもみんなたくさんありがとう！
Thank you everyone! Thank you so much to all the members too!
ああ、なんか、ここまでやっとこれたなみたいな。
Ah, like, I finally made it this far...
ああ、嬉しいです、本当に。
Ah, I'm really happy.
ああ、豊洲ライブでね、曲をみんなに聴いてもらって、なんか、あれらしいことができたりなんかして。
Ah, getting people to listen to songs at the Toyosu Live, and doing things like that...
で、やっとこのお披露めの舞台で、あの、こんなに究極ですよ、究極。
And finally on this reveal stage, like, this is the ultimate, ultimate.
いや、まだ7曲しか経ってないけど、究極をもたしてもらえる、なんていい世界なんだろう！
Well, it's only been 7 songs, but to be able to reach the ultimate... what a wonderful world!
回れ回れメリコラウ... あ、これダメ？これちょっとダメかな。
Spin around spin around Melicorau... Ah, is this no good? Is this a bit no good?
次の歌これとかじゃないからね！あ、新曲！
The next song isn't something like this! Ah, new song!
あ、楽しい。このね、ステージも見てください！
Ah, fun. Look at this stage too!
かわいいでしょ！すいちゃん仕様にしてもらいました。ほらほらほらほらほらほら、星がいっぱい散りばめられている。
Isn't it cute? They made it Suisei style. Look look look, stars are scattered everywhere.
こんなところで座れちゃったりもしちゃう。
You can even sit in a place like this.
はあ、疲れたわ。
Ha, I'm tired.
じゃあ、皆さん、ついにね、あと2曲となりましたけれども、にゅ、ねやばばば。
Well everyone, finally there are only 2 songs left, nyu, ne, yabababa.
すみません、テイクスでおねがいします。テイクス、あ、はいはい、すまんで、はい。
Sorry, take 2 please. Take 2, ah, yes yes, sorry, yes.
それでは、皆さん、ええ、あと2曲となりましたけれども、あと2曲続けて頑張って歌いたいと思います。
Well then everyone, um, there are only 2 songs left, but I'll do my best to sing 2 more songs continuously.
この2曲は、きっとみんな、みんな知ってる曲ですので、ぜひ一緒に乗って、一緒に歌っててくれたら、画面の前でサイリウムを振って、一緒に歌ってくれたら嬉しいです。
These 2 songs are definitely songs everyone knows, so I'd be happy if you ride along, sing along, wave your glowsticks in front of the screen, and sing together with me.
それでは、次の曲、いきます！
Well then, next song, let's go!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats resonate!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and the best friends,
キラメキに乗って☆
Ride the sparkle☆
イェーイ
Yeah!
覚えてるかな？
Do you remember?
初めての歌
My very first song
なつかしいね
So nostalgic
私の声が震えてた
My voice was trembling
ほんの少し
Just a little bit
あの日から続く未来はみんなと掴んだ今日だよ
The future continuing from that day is today, grasped together with everyone!
もっともっともっともっともっと加速するハート
More and more, accelerating heart,
いっしょに行くよどこまでも
Together, we'll go anywhere!
are you ready ? 準備はok ?
Are you ready? Is your preparation OK?
ひらけ！！夢のトビラを (123)
Open!! The door of dreams (1, 2, 3)
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
ここにあるよ 見つけてくれたから
It's right here, because you found me,
きみに会いたくてやって来たんだよ
I came here because I wanted to meet you.
みんなで歌おう
Let's sing together,
終わらないメロディ
An unending melody,
キラメキに乗って☆
Ride the sparkle☆
行くよどこまでも
We'll go anywhere!
準備はok ?
Is your preparation OK?
ひらけ！夢のトビラを (123)
Open! The door of dreams (1, 2, 3)
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats resonate!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and the best friends,
ここにいるよ
I'm right here!
見つけてくれた感動
The emotion of you finding me...
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ
I came here because I wanted to see you,
みんなで歌おう
let's all sing together!
笑えないメロディ
A melody that can't make you smile,
きらめきにのって
riding on the sparkling light.
届いてるかな 私の声
I wonder if my voice is reaching you,
届けたいのは 君に笑顔
what I want to deliver is a smile to you.
理想の高さに 悔やして
Regretting the height of my ideals,
みんなと泣き笑ったね
crying and laughing together with everyone.
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと すべて抱きしめて
Tightly, tightly, tightly, tightly embracing everything,
行こう どこまでも 準備はOK
let's go anywhere, we're ready to go!
すすめ 希望の道を
Advance down the path of hope!
1 2 3 きらめきライトダンス
1, 2, 3, sparkling light dance!
好きな気持ちからぶんにかなでたいな
Playing out from my favorite feelings,
最高な場所 最高なみんなと
in the best place, with everyone at our best!
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
I'm right here, it's no illusion.
君の心が 幸せに染まるように 重ねてくハーモニー きらめき纏って
So that your heart dyes in happiness, piling up harmonies, draped in sparkle.
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな そんな願いにはわがままもいいでしょ
Wanting to keep singing, wanting to keep dancing, isn't a bit of selfishness okay for such a wish?
だって楽しすぎても止まらない 輝くステージで もっともっとずっと
Because it's too fun to stop, on the shining stage, more and more, forever!
ずーーーっと！
Fo--rever!
みんな今日もありがとう！ つづきつづいてみんなのおかげで ここまで来れました！
Thank you everyone today too! Continuing on, thanks to everyone, I've made it this far!
嬉しい楽しい愛しだけじゃ語れない 今も今もあるけど
It can't be expressed with just happy, fun, and love, though there are worries right now too.
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ 君と同じ世界を見つめてて いくよ！
I'm right here, I'm right here, gazing at the same world as you. Let's go!
きらめきライトダンス
Sparkling light dance!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make newborn heartbeats echo!
最高な時間 最高な仲間と ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたんだ
With the best time and best friends, I'm right here, you found me.
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
I came here because I wanted to see you, let's all sing together!
笑えないメロディ きらめきにのって きらめき纏って
A melody that can't make you smile, riding on the sparkling light, draped in sparkle.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あの空で輝いた流れ星を追いかけて
Chasing the shooting star that shone in that sky,
いつか君を照らすから 星製のスターライト
so I can someday illuminate you, starlight of Hoshimachi!
生まれたばかりの小さな光は 消えてしまいそうな声で歌を歌ったんだ
The newborn little light sang a song with a voice that seemed like it might fade away.
誰かに届くようにそっとその声を振り絞って 今はまだ響かないけどいつかその心に
Straining that voice softly so it would reach someone, it doesn't resonate yet now, but someday in that heart...
満天の星を降らせよう 眩いほどきらめくよ 何もかも忘れるくらい飛びっきりのステージを
Let's rain down a sky full of stars, sparkling so dazzlingly, an extraordinary stage so wonderful you'll forget everything else!
声は眠れない
My voice won't let me sleep,
ほどに胸を躍らせて
making my heart race so much.
手を取って さぁ行こう
Take my hand, let's go now
星生のスターライト
to the starlight of our birth.
Let's go!
叶えたい 願いを
The wish I want to come true,
浮かべた光は すれ違いで愛を待ってる
the floating light is waiting for love as we cross paths.
早く見つけてよ
Find me soon.
理想を描いただけじゃ
Just drawing ideals
きっと前に進めない
surely won't let me move forward.
踏み出したばかりだけど いつかその胸に
I've only just stepped out, but someday in that heart...
満開の花を咲かせよ
Let's make full-bloomed flowers bloom,
宇宙にしてみせるから
turning it into a universe.
次元さえも越えるくらい 飛び切りのドリームを
With a dream so extraordinary it transcends dimensions,
あげる 今夜は覚めないで
I'll give it to you. Don't wake up tonight.
一度きりの瞬間だって
Even if it's just a fleeting moment,
大事なのは ほら行くよ
what matters is... look, here we go.
星生のスターライト
To the starlight of our birth.
Let's go!
数え切れないほどの星がそれぞれ違う色で光っているんだ
Countless stars are each shining in different colors.
その中で私は何が残せるのかな きっと
In the midst of that, what will I leave behind? Surely,
誰よりも青く 強い光を
brighter and bluer than anyone else's strong light.
まん丸の星を降らせよ
Let's make round stars fall down,
眩いほど煌めくよ
sparkling so dazzlingly.
何もかも忘れるくらい 飛び切りのステージを
With a stage so extraordinary you'll forget everything,
あげる 今夜は覚めないで
I'll give it to you. Don't wake up tonight.
一度きりの瞬間だって 私のこと見ていてね
Even if it's a once-in-a-lifetime moment, keep your eyes on me.
星生のスターライト
To the starlight of our birth.
みんな！コメット！やっと歌えました！
Everyone! Comet! We finally sang it!
スイちゃんは 今日の会え...
Sui-chan's today's meet—!
みんな！明日はい晴れるってずっと信じてます！
Everyone! I've always believed tomorrow will be clear!
みんな！いつか！今度は大きな会場で！
Everyone! Someday! At a huge venue next time!
星生のスターライト
Starlight of our birth.
はい、えー、いかがだったでしょうか？
So, um, how was it?
キャメライライダーとコラボしたりした
I collaborated with Camellia-rider and...
あ、終わったと思った？終わったと思ったでしょ？終わったと思ったそこあなたにちょっと告知をしに戻ってきたんです。
Ah, did you think it was over? You thought it was over, right? I came back to give you an announcement right there where you thought it was over.
普通のライブだったら今のとこで終わったけど、
In a normal live stream, it would have ended right there, but
えーっと、じゃあね、告知をしたいと思います。
um, well then, I'd like to make an announcement.
星街すいせい、こうやって歌を歌っておりますけれども、ちゃんとね、歌の動画も用意しているんですよ！
Hoshimachi Suisei, I'm singing songs like this, but you know, I also prepare song videos!
では最初にこちら！エンゼルフィッシュ、天音かなたとうたいました！3月投稿予定、
First, here! 'Angelfish', I sang it with Amane Kanata! Scheduled to be posted in March,
もうすぐすぐ、もう上旬とかになるんじゃないかなと思っております！もうイラストからして可愛くない？
it'll probably be around early March, right? Aren't the illustrations alone super cute?
もうね、本当に最高、
It's really the best,
本当に最高な音になってるんで、音？音？違う違う違う、音源！
it has truly the best sound—sound? Sound? No no no, sound source!
最高な音源に仕上がっておりますので、お楽しみに！
It's finished with the best sound source, so look forward to it!
ではでは二人目、こちら！佐賀事変！星街すいせいかけるホロライブファンタジー、3期生のみんなに声をかけて、ちょっとコーラスみたいなところで参加してもらいました！
Now then, second one, here! 'Saga Jihen'! Hoshimachi Suisei x Hololive Fantasy, I called out to everyone in the 3rd gen and had them participate in a chorus part!
佐賀事変、めっちゃいい曲、絶対歌いたいと思った時、すぐ体が動いていた。何を歌うか分からねえと重いが完全に動いていたんだ！
'Saga Jihen' is such a good song. When I thought 'I definitely want to sing it,' my body started moving immediately. Even though I didn't know what I was singing, my body was moving!
ということで、こちら4月投稿予定ですので、こちらも お楽しみに！
So, this is scheduled to be posted in April, so please look forward to this as well!
もうこれもね、最高に音源となっております！もうこれは、もうなんかつまりスペシャル、スペシャル、もうなんか、いい言葉が出てこないから、ごい...
This too has an amazing sound source! This is, like, a special, special... well, good words aren't coming out, so...
違う、違う！
Wait, no, no!
ごめん、あ、あん……
Sorry, ah... um...
ウィアー！ ウィアー！ ウィアー！ あ、んっ……
We are! We are! We are! Ah...
はい！
Okay!
ではね、えーこんな感じで、星街すいせい、ついにこんな動ける動けるカメラをご用意していただいたんですけれども、
Well, like this, Hoshimachi Suisei has finally been provided with a camera that can move around like this...
屈伸とかしちゃお？あ、これ屈伸じゃない！
Shall I do some squats? Ah, that's not a squat!
あ、屈伸！
Ah, squats!
いや、本当に嬉しくて、もう嬉しすぎて、もうずっと、ずっと動きまくってて、もうなんか……
I mean, I'm really so happy, so overly happy, that I've just been moving around nonstop, and like...
あの、すいせいさん、大丈夫ですか？あのライブ前に体力減らさないでくださいねみたいな
"Suisei-san, are you okay? Please don't drain your stamina before the live," like that.
めっちゃ怒られてたぐらいなんですけども、なんかでもライブでも本当に、もうこんなにもパワフルな力が出るのかな、なん、ごめん、な、何言いたいんだろ？
I got pretty heavily scolded about that, but you know, even during lives, I really wonder if I can put out this much powerful energy—wait, sorry, what am I even trying to say?
みたいな感じで、もうなんか全ての力を出し切りました！
Like, yeah, I gave it my absolute all!
もっとこれからも成長して、今よりも素晴らしいパフォーマンスを次の何かのステージでお見せできるように日々精進してまいりますので！
I'll keep growing from here on out and work hard every day so that I can show you an even more wonderful performance on some future stage!
星街すいせいをこれからもよろしくお願いします！いってきまーす！
Please continue to support Hoshimachi Suisei! I'm off!
はい、では、えっと、これ、つぶやいてる？つぶやいてね。大事だよ。よろしくね。
Right, well, um, are you tweeting this? Be sure to tweet it. It's important. Please do.
では！名残惜しいですけども、あ、なんか名残惜しい！もう終わりだなんて、ありえない！え、もう笑わせんの？え？
Well! It's so hard to part ways, ah, I hate leaving! It can't be ending already! Eh, are you making me laugh already? Huh?
ってことで、あと、あと15曲とか20曲歌いたかったけど！でもまた別の機会にしましょう！
That being said, I wanted to sing another 15 or 20 songs, but let's save that for another occasion!
みんなさ、また会いましょう！バイバーイ！じゃあね、じゃあね、ちゃっちゃく、ちゃっちゃく、ちゃっちゃく……
Everyone, let's meet again! Bye-bye! See ya, see ya, cha-cha-k, cha-cha-k, cha-cha-k...